{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Who is the father of Computers?",
      "options": [
        "James Gosling",
        "Charles Babbage",
        "Dennis Ritchie",
        "Bjarne Stroustrup"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of CPU?",
      "options": [
        "Computer Processing Unit",
        "Computer Principle Unit",
        "Central Processing Unit",
        "Control Processing Unit"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct definition of Computer?",
      "options": [
        "Computer is a machine or device that can be programmed to perform arithmetical or logic operation sequences automatically",
        "Computer understands only binary language which is written in the form of 0s & 1s",
        "Computer is a programmable electronic device that stores, retrieves, and processes the data",
        "All of the mentioned"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following language does the computer understand?",
      "options": [
        "Computer understands only C Language",
        "Computer understands only Assembly Language",
        "Computer understands only Binary Language",
        "Computer understands only BASIC"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following computer language is written in binary codes only?",
      "options": ["pascal", "machine language", "C#", "C"],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the brain of the computer?",
      "options": [
        "Central Processing Unit",
        "Memory",
        "Arithmetic and Logic unit",
        "Control unit"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are the input devices that enable direct data entry into a computer system from source documents?",
      "options": [
        "System Access devices",
        "Data acquiring devices",
        "Data retrieving devices",
        "Data Scanning devices"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a computer?",
      "options": ["Versatility", "Accuracy", "Diligence", "I.Q."],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the smallest unit of data in a computer?",
      "options": ["Bit", "KB", "Nibble", "Byte"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can access the server?",
      "options": ["Web Client", "User", "Web Browser", "Web Server"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": " Which of the following unit is responsible for converting the data received from the user into a computer understandable format?",
      "options": [
        "Output Unit",
        "Input Unit",
        "Memory Unit",
        "Arithmetic & Logic Unit"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following monitor looks like a television and are normally used with non-portable computer systems?",
      "options": ["LED", "LCD", "CRT", "Flat Panel Monitors"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of computer code?",
      "options": ["EDIC", "ASCII", "BCD", "EBCDIC"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following part of a processor contains the hardware necessary to perform all the operations required by a computer?",
      "options": ["Controller", "Registers", "Cache", "Data path"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is designed to control the operations of a computer?",
      "options": [
        "User",
        "Application Software",
        "System Software",
        "Utility Software"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    }
  ]
}
